<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[davidosomething.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[Web developer; super handsome. This is my personal website.]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 06:35:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidosomething.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Lint your markdown files with gulp‑remark‑lint‑dko]]></title><description><![CDATA[I've just published on npm, my gulp plugin to lint markdown files using remark and remark-lint. It's fully functional right now, and you can install it from npm to start using it in your gulpfile: npm install --save-dev gulp-remark-lint-dko I am planning to add more features, which you can follow in the README or help contribute with a pull request. gulp-remark-lint-dko on GitHub gulp-remark-lint-dko on npmjs.com Here's a screenshot of the output: ]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/gulp-markdown-linter/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/gulp-markdown-linter/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Whitespace settings in Vim]]></title><description><![CDATA[For any good programmer, consistent whitespace is a measure of code-quality. Vim has a lot of built-in settings and features for handling whitespace, and this article will go over those with the examples the Vim help pages lack. For the purposes of this article, tabs are represented as blocks of the character: ░. Settings This section pertains to Vim's built-in settings flags. You can use :help 'somesettingname' with single quotes from within in Vim to see the full details, so the most useful&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/whitespace-in-vim/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/whitespace-in-vim/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Setting up Vim for JavaScript development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Before you read any of this I will caveat with the fact that Vim is perfectly adequate for modern JavaScript development without plugins. The Vim runtime comes with syntax highlighting and omni-completion already, and you can even configure Vim as a task runner without plugins. This is geared towards people who already know how to use Vim. E.g., if you understand minutiae like the difference between set autoindent and set indentexpr, and have found neither to your liking, then read on. Otherwise&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/vim-for-javascript/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/vim-for-javascript/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rebuilding davidosomething.com as a static site]]></title><description><![CDATA[I've rebuilt my website from the ground-up for the new year, finishing it just in time. This site is now fully static, templates in Handlebars syntax and posts written in Markdown are combined into plain old HTML, where WordPress and PHP were previously providing the templating and storing the post formatting as HTML in a database. The new stack Replaced PHP templating with Handlebars Replaced WordPress serving with Metalsmith generation Replaced MySQL storage engine with Markdown files in git&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/rebuilding-davidosomethingcom-as-a-static-site/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/rebuilding-davidosomethingcom-as-a-static-site/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[grunt-wendy – CasperJS for GruntJS]]></title><description><![CDATA[ grunt-wendy is my latest Grunt plugin. It’s a CasperJS test runner with customizable filtering and formatting options, which CasperJS alone lacks. Installation npm install --save-dev grunt-wendy See the docs and contribute to grunt-wendy on the GitHub repository here: grunt-wendy on GitHub VS others Compared to iamchrismiller/grunt-casper and ronaldlokers/grunt-casperjs, the top two Grunt CasperJS test runners (all others are no longer maintained), this task: adds formatting options to format&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/grunt-wendy-casperjs/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/grunt-wendy-casperjs/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[git-my]]></title><description><![CDATA[Git doesn’t track who created branches. This makes it difficult to keep track of your own branches when you have a lot of them checked out locally. To remedy this, I wrote a shell script that gets all the remote git branches and filters them out based on the last committer. It then lists the ones where you were the last committer. You can find the script here: https://github.com/davidosomething/git-my Here’s a screenshot of it in action: ]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/git-my/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/git-my/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux on the Lenovo Thinkpad W510 – Part 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[The NVidia drivers after 343.22 no longer support the NVidia Quadro FX 880M GPU for the ThinkPad W510 so I had to switch to legacy drivers (340-xx). To get everything working again, I make some changes to my kernel mode settings and my xorg.conf. In /boot/syslinux/syslinux.cfg and /etc/xorg.conf.d/20-nvidia.conf I am now using this: And in the syslinux.cfg the line DEFAULT arch is now DEFAULT archnvidia to default to the new kernel settings. ]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510-part-3/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510-part-3/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[How I Work (2014)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Creating a website is just not as simple as it used to be. In order to do things right, I need all kinds of tools: compilers, linters, package managers, optimizers and minifiers, etc. Aside from that I need to consider things like portability, organization, and maintainability. I just started a new job so I’ve had some time to think about the cleanest way to get everything installed and organized. I follow some basic rules to keep my environments clean. Here are the principles I follow and the&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/how-i-work/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/how-i-work/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux on the Lenovo ThinkPad W510 – Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m leaving Linux Mint 16 behind. The RC for Linux Mint 17 is out so maybe that will fix some things, but the main problem I’ve had is with installing packages. Apt just doesn’t cut it, especially when I think back to when I was using ArchLinux. So I’m going back to Arch and the next post will be about that. Apt’s greatest downfall is that as you add PPAs and when you start needing multiple architectures, the dependency chain breaks and is almost impossible to fix. Hardware Upgrades Since I got&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510-part-2/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510-part-2/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux on the Lenovo ThinkPad W510]]></title><description><![CDATA[I bought a crappy PC laptop as a backup since my MacBook’s been failing. I’ve gone full Linux on it since I spend most of the day in a terminal and browser, so except for Photoshop I’m comfortable. I’ll probably buy a new MacBook when they release 2014 Pro Retina ones. Until then, I’ll document my experience here. First off, I’m running Linux Mint 16 Petra with the Cinnamon Desktop Environment. I’ve got to say, it’s really pretty in comparison to Windows 7 that the laptop came with and Windows 8&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/linux-lenovo-thinkpad-w510/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[grunt-toggl]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Start using grunt-toggl today! npm install --save-dev grunt-toggl See the docs and contribute to grunt-toggl on the GitHub repository here: https://github.com/davidosomething/grunt-toggl Some background I work for many clients and on multiple projects at a time, so it’s important to keep track of my billable hours. My tool of choice for time tracking is Toggl. Check it out if you’re not already a user — it’s got apps for every device and OS and a great reporting dashboard. Sometimes I forget to&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/grunt-toggl/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/grunt-toggl/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[First week developing on a Mac]]></title><description><![CDATA[The following is a whining session about developing on OSX. It’s not all bad. I had been using an old (2004) DELL machine at work with Windows XP. Needless to say, the machine was pagefaulting and had a bunch of problems with its RAM. So they finally got me a new computer to work on — a 24″ iMac with an i3 processor. Not exactly a beast, but it’s a big upgrade. I was using Notepad++ on my PC and I am ridiculously fast on it. Maybe it’s a sad thing, but I’ve never seen anyone move lines and&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/first-week-developing-on-a-mac/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/first-week-developing-on-a-mac/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shuttle PC - new harddrive, Clonezilla &#038; Windows 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[I bought a new harddrive on sale after Cyber Monday to replace the 250 GB harddrive in my Shuttle. It’s a bare drive, which means it doesn’t come with a SATA cable or box. Now I’ve got a total of 2 TB of storage with 1 TB already full. I used my super-difficult-to-open Lacie case (pried it open with scissors) to house and connect the bare drive while I formatted it. This was a time when I really wished I had an eSata dock or enclosure. I did a full format rather than quick; the difference is&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/shuttle-pc-new-harddrive-clonezilla-windows-7/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/shuttle-pc-new-harddrive-clonezilla-windows-7/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Development Setup]]></title><description><![CDATA[Although I primarily develop on a Windows PC, I still consider Linux (also Unix and OSX) the most powerful and practical environment for setting up web and database servers, DNS, and version control repositories (as a master on DVCS). A few of the benefits include: Using SSH to connect to a Linux commandline is faster compared to RDP’ing or VNC’ing into a Windows machine (also saves battery life on smartphones). Cygwin is a slow alternative. Package management for easy (and frequent) upgrades&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/my-development-setup/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/my-development-setup/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shuttle PC - Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[I didn’t read the parts compatibility guide online before buying the RAM and graphics cards so the Shuttle wasn’t working up until last week. Since I couldn’t see anything for lack of graphics and I don’t have another DDR3 compatible machine lying around, I couldn’t test the parts. Shuttle PCs don’t beep on POST so I couldn’t even tell if the motherboard and CPU worked (power and fans worked though). The only way to proceed would be to buy a new compatible graphics card and RAM. It turns out the&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/shuttle-pc-part-2/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/shuttle-pc-part-2/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Putting together my new Shuttle PC]]></title><description><![CDATA[Feeling a bit prodigious, I bought a Shuttle PC the other day (SH55). It totally looks like a toaster, but it’s cool. It’s going to be an always-on HTPC for the living room. I am completely out of the consumer PC hardware loop and ended up getting the i7-860 (1156) instead of an i5. The major, major difference for these two would be the availability of integrated graphics on the i5, vs two extra cores on the i7. Wish I had gotten the i5, since then I would be able to play with the PC immediately&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/putting-together-my-new-shuttle-pc/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/putting-together-my-new-shuttle-pc/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Event Apart DC 2010]]></title><description><![CDATA[So I just got back from the Washington, DC iteration of An Event Apart. I feel that if you follow all the speakers’ blogs and read Smashing Magazine’s content (or nontent, as it is), they’re really just saying the same thing. The real experience is paying to see these pioneers and policy-makers speak live and network with them (they are easily approachable at the conference or at the after parties). The key message this year has been to stop trying to make your site look the same in every&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/takeaways-from-an-event-apart-dc-2010/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/takeaways-from-an-event-apart-dc-2010/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Honda Metropolitan in Boston]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Honda Metropolitan is a 49cc gas-powered scooter. Because of its small size and vehicle classification, it is a very convenient mode of transportation in Boston, where the streets are crowded and parking is expensive. I did some research on the Honda Met to help out a new owner, and wanted to post a compendium of all the information I found (a lot in some areas, not so much in others). I’m not the expert, the members of urbanscootin.com are, so massive props to them! Some of these are&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/honda-metropolitan-in-boston/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/honda-metropolitan-in-boston/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tips for Faster PSD to HTML Conversions]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ever wonder how those PSD to HTML services do the job with such a quick turnaround, sometimes guaranteeing valid code in 24 hours on even the most complex PSDs? The task is roughly 40% breaking up the PSD logically, 20% coding, and 40% moving elements around until everything fits together. Here are some tips I’ve learned from years of experience and trying to find new techniques in those tutorials the web has too many of. Contents Photoshop Techniques Save for Web Convert to Smart Object&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/tips-faster-psd-html-conversions/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/tips-faster-psd-html-conversions/index.html</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[jQRPG — An Old-School Style RPG in jQuery]]></title><description><![CDATA[JavaScript/jQuery and CSS compatibility is finally at a decent state amongst major browsers (IE and ACID3 notwithstanding). At least, similar/the same DOM manipulation behavior can be reproduced across those browsers. Not only that, but the JavaScript rendering speed of engines other than Trident (IE’s) is quite fast. With these developments, it is actually possible to create playable games (really, check those links out!). The Demo In about 4 hours I’ve created a demo RPG here using jQuery&#x2026;]]></description><link>https://davidosomething.com/blog/jqrpg-an-old-school-style-rpg-in-jquery/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidosomething.com/blog/jqrpg-an-old-school-style-rpg-in-jquery/index.html</guid></item></channel></rss>